https://github.com/probinso

Personal Statement

I am currently a masters student at OHSU, studying computer science with a focus in signal processing and machine learning. In my several years of industry experience and prior degree, I developed strong interests in cryptography, reproducible research, statistical computing, and programming languages. I have adapted to, and adopted, a new or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has also gained me strong communication skills.

Persistant Experience :

C, C++ Pvthon Linux TDD

R, dplyr $\mathbb{E}T_{F,X}$ Git. Ticketing Systems

Work Experience _

- Graduate Research Intern NASA Jet Propulsion Lab

June 2018 - Sept. 2018

Designed prototype system from meetings with top NASA employees for mission risk assesment Developed Subject Matter Expert identifier, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Technologies: Python, gensim, pandas, jupyter

OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab - Research Support Engineer

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to workflows and analytics tools for studying Microbiome populations Supported research on developing brains, including ABCD, and several ADHD/ASD studies Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI images

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab

Contractor/Consultant

RGB Optics / C&W Energy USA

Nov. 2015 - Present

Developed low cost spectral profile analysis and custom photo image processing Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Developed a cloud memoizing data pipeline for caching computationally expensive operations Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild June 2016 Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable remote-first workflow Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++, Jira, ZenHub

- Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015 Galois Inc.

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Technologies : C, C++, Python, SQLite, Subversion

- Mentors Program Director Sept. 2009 - March 2012 Computer Science Dept.

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Technologies: Ada, C++, Scheme, R, mercurial

Neato Projects

Whale vocals localization and analysis jupyter, matplotlib Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, b. Morphological Watershedding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, Relevance Vector Machine	eash, github.api
Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk,	sklearn, Python
Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor	R, caret
Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, S.	agemath, Python
Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module	agemath, Erlang
Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions	R, Perl
AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System	Ada
Fractal Art Generator	C#
Image Manipulation Program	C#
Unix Shell	С
Liars Dice Game Server	С

Education

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Courses :

Digital Signal Processing
Problem Solving with Large Clusters
Image Processing
Machine Learning
Information Retrieval

Computing Ethics Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Analysis of Sequences

Western Washington University

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Computer Science